If you were somebody who responded to seeing videos of individuals being snatched up out the street, taken from their families and sent to God knows where, Alligator Alcatraz, Seacott Prison in El Salvador, you know, a number of any distinct places that are not back home with their families.
If you were somebody who watched that and said they voted for this, you are not qualified to tell anybody about empathy and where they should apply it.
And this is the type of hypocrisy that we have to face and address head on if we want to really understand why us as U.S.ians, people in this country, are so disconnected from the rest of the globe.
We don't even understand empathy.
And we definitely don't understand when it should be applied.
Empathy is distinctively powerful.
It is an energy exchange that connects our beings.
Thus, the United States and capitalism has done a really good job of really dispelling it and not engaging in how to teach us to use it, to manage it, to amplify it.
Empathy is powerful.
My empathy for the Palestinians became so deeply connected that it literally gave me IBS.
TMI, but for real.
So it is not something that can be wielded willy-nilly, particularly in spaces where it is not regarded.
Your empathy is the language of your soul.
So when those of us who are empathic talk about empathy, we are talking about how we are choosing to engage our soul in practices of caring, in practices of healing, and in practices of engagement.
And we are discernment, and we are discernful, is that a word?
It is today, of when it is purposeful to do so.
And I wish everyone the time and the capability to do that work for themselves.
Support a real one.